A Guide to the Markle Foundation records, Record Group 1-Record Group 3 FA024
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Markle Foundation Programs, 1
  - Markle Foundation Programs - Accession 2, 2; 24 Cubic Feet
    - Grants in Communications (1984-1989), 1981-1994; 2; 9 Cubic Feet 9 boxes
      - Markle Foundation - SeniotNet Retreat - Edith Bjornson, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 197)
        D90103.
        See also Box 8, Folders 247-255: University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project.
      - Markle Foundation - Reprint Service - Steve Savage, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 198)
        D90208.
      - University of Maryland - Judith Lichtenberg, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 199)
        D86332.
      - University of Maryland - Jay G. Blumler, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 200)
        G87220.
      - University of Maryland - Jay G. Blumler, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 201)
        G89215.
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - W. Russell Neuman, 1984-1990 (Box 7, Folder 202)
        G86214.
      - University of Michigan - Michael Lougee, 1985-1988 (Box 7, Folder 203)
        G85326.
      - University of Michigan - Michael Lougee, 1985-1988 (Box 7, Folder 204)
        G85326. Evaluation plan.
      - University of Michigan - Formative Evaluation Research Associates, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 205)
        D86334.
      - National Bureau of Standards - Roy G. Saltman, 1987-1992 (Box 7, Folder 206)
        G87101.
      - National Bureau of Standards - Roy G. Saltman, 1987-1992 (Box 7, Folder 207)
        G87101. Financial reports.
      - National Foundation for Improvement of Education - KIDSNET - Karen W. Jaffe, 1985-1988 (Box 7, Folder 208)
        G86104.
      - National Foundation for Improvement of Education - KIDSNET - Karen W. Jaffe, 1985-1988 (Box 7, Folder 209)
      - National Public Radio - G. Gail Crotts, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 210)
        G81214.
      - National Public Radio - G. Gail Crotts, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 211)
      - National Public Radio - Thomas Warnock, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 212)
        G83101.
      - National Public Radio - Douglas Bennet, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 213)
        G86331.
      - New York Community Trust - Kit Conroy, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 214)
        D94107.
      - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers, 1980, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 215)
        D84109.
      - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers - Arnold Shore, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 216)
        D85112.
      - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 217)
        D85330.
      - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers - Barbara Bryan, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 218)
        D88110.
      - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers - David M. Nee, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 219)
        D88332.
      - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers - Hildy Simmons, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 220)
        D89321.
      - North Carolina Agency for Public Telecommunications - Lee Wing, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 221)
        D85219.
      - North Carolina Agency for Public Telecommunications - Lee Wing, 1985-1992 (Box 7, Folder 222)
        D87108.
      - North Carolina Agency for Public Telecommunications - Lee Wing, 1985-1992 (Box 7, Folder 223)
      - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill - Philip Meyer, 1985-1993 (Box 7, Folder 224)
        G86219.
      - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill - Mark E. Williams, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 225)
        D89320.
      - University of Pennsylvania - "Journal of Communication" - Marsha Siefert, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 226)
        G88337.
      - Public Agenda Foundation - Deborah Wadsworth, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 227)
        D88215.
      - Public Agenda Foundation - Deborah Wadsworth, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 228)
        G89104.
      - Public Agenda Foundation - Deborah Wadsworth, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 229)
        G89104. Printed material.
      - Public Broadcasting Service - Stephen D. Atlas, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 230)
        G88220.
      - Queens College of the City of New York - Gaye Tuchman, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 231)
        G85327.
      - RAND Corporation - David Lyons, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 232)
        D85113.
      - RAND Corporation - David Lyons, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 233)
        D85113. Progress and final reports.
      - RAND Corporation - Stanley M. Besen and Leland Johnson, 1985-1989, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 234)
        G86102.
      - RAND Corporation - Stanley M. Besen and Leland Johnson, 1985-1989, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 235)
      - RAND Corporation - Stanley M. Besen and Leland Johnson, 1985-1989, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 236)
        G86102. Printed material.
      - RAND Corporation - Tora Bikson, 1985-1989 (Box 8, Folder 237)
        G86329.
      - RAND Corporation - Tora Bikson, 1985-1989 (Box 8, Folder 238)
        G86329. Proposal.
      - RAND Corporation - Tora Bikson, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 239)
        G87107.
      - RAND Corporation - Tora Bikson, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 240)
        G87107. Reports and printed material.
      - RAND Corporation - Tora Bikson, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 241)
        G88334.
      - RAND Corporation - Tora Bikson, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 242)
        G88334. Proposal and background material.
      - RAND Corporation - Tora Bikson, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 243)
        G88334. Reports.
      - RAND Corporation - Leland Johnson, 1988-1993 (Box 8, Folder 244)
        G89105.
      - RAND Corporation - Leland Johnson, 1988-1993 (Box 8, Folder 245)
      - RAND Corporation - Leland Johnson, 1988-1993 (Box 8, Folder 246)
        G89105. Papers and reports.
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project - Mary Furlong, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 247)
        G86103.
        See also Box 7, Folder 197: Markle Foundation - SeniorNet Retreat - Edith Bjornson, 1989 (D90103).
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project - Mary Furlong, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 248)
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project - Mary Furlong, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 249)
        G87106.
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project - Mary Furlong, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 250)
        G88106.
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project - Mary Furlong, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 251)
        G88333.
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project - Mary Furlong, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 252)
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project - Mary Furlong, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 253)
        G90107.
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project, 1984-1988 (Box 8, Folder 254)
        Newsclips.
      - University of San Francisco - SeniorNet Project, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 255)
        Program Officer's file.
      - Social Science Research Council - Robert Pearson, 1987-1992 (Box 9, Folder 256)
        G88224.
      - University of Southern California - Annenberg School of Communications, 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 257)
        G87110.
      - University of Southern California - Annenberg School of Communications - Tracy Westen, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 258)
        D88108.
      - University of Southern California - Annenberg School of Communications - Tracy Westen, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 259)
        D88217.
      - University of Southern California - Annenberg School of Communications - Tracy Westen, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 260)
      - Stanford University - Donald F. Roberts, 1985-1989 (Box 9, Folder 261)
        G86105.
      - Stanford University - Gavriel Salomon, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 262)
        D86112.
      - Stanford University - Stanford Law School - Paul Goldstein, 1986-1993 (Box 9, Folder 263)
        G87218.
      - Stanford University - Center for Economic Policy Research - Roger Noll, 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 264)
        G87219.
      - Stein Gerontological Institute - Sara Czaja, 1987-1992 (Box 9, Folder 265)
        G88103.
      - Stein Gerontological Institute - Sara Czaja, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 266)
        D90320.
      - Syracuse University - Thomas E. Patterson, 1983-1987 (Box 9, Folder 267)
        D83339.
      - Syracuse University - Thomas E. Patterson, 1987-1992 (Box 9, Folder 268)
        D88214.
      - Tarrant County Junior College - Sam Krhovjak, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 269)
        D89212.
      - Tel Aviv University - Gavriel Salomon, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 270)
        D86111.
      - Telecommunications Policy Research Conference - Charles L. Jackson, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 271)
        G88338.
      - Telecommunications Policy Research Conference - Charles L. Jackson, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 272)
        G88338. Financial reports.
      - Telecommunications Policy Research Conference - Charles L. Jackson, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 273)
        G88338. Reports and conference materials.
      - Television Audience Assessment, Inc. - Elizabeth J. Roberts, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 274)
        G85007.
      - Television Audience Assessment, Inc. - Rolf M. Wulfsberg, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 275)
        G85215-PRI.
      - Television Audience Assessment, Inc. - Rolf M. Wulfsberg, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 276)
        G85215-PRI. Business partners (potential).
      - Television Audience Assessment, Inc. - Rolf M. Wulfsberg, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 277)
        G852154-PRI. Venture capital project.
      - Television Audience Assessment, Inc. - Rolf M. Wulfsberg, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 278)
        G86001-PRI.
      - Television Audience Assessment, Inc., 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 279)
        After official close.
      - WGBH Educational Foundation - Stephen D. Atlas, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 280)
        D88111.
- Markle Foundation Administration, 2
  Subgroup 1 - Markle Foundation Administration - Accession 1
  Subgroup 2 - Markle Foundation Administration - Accession 2
  - Markle Foundation Administration - Accession 1, 1; 8 Cubic Feet
    This subgroup is arranged in five series:
    Series 1 - Board of Directors
    Series 2 - Financial Material
    Series 3 - Publications
    Series 4 - Presidents' Papers
    Series 5 - Studies, Surveys, and Miscellaneous
    - Board of Directors, 1927-1980; 1; 5.5 Cubic Feet 11 boxes
      This series is arranged in 4 subseries:
      Subseries 1 - Minutes
      Subseries 2 - Meeting Agendas
      Subseries 3 - Progress Reports
      Subseries 4 - Collected Reprints
      - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1927-1979; 1
        - 1927-January 1933, 1927-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
          Includes Charter and Constitution.
        - November 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - 1936-June 1939, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - October 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - 1950-1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - 1958-1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
        - 1971-March 1978, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - April 1978-March 1980, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Executive Committee, 1933-1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - Board of Directors - Minutes - Microfilm (Reel 1, Reel 2, Reel 3)
      - Board of Directors - Meeting Agendas, 1946-1980; 2
        - 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - 1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - 1956 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - 1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - 1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - 1960 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - 1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        - 1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
        - 1963 (Box 6, Folder 14)
        - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
        - 1965 (Box 6, Folder 16)
        - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 17)
        - 1967 (Box 6, Folder 18)
        - 1968 (Box 6, Folder 19)
        - 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 20)
        - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
        - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 22)
        - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 23)
        - 1974 (Box 7, Folder 24)
        - 1975 (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - 1976 (Box 8, Folder 26)
        - 1977 (Box 8, Folder 27)
        - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 28)
        - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 29)
        - 1980 (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Board of Directors - Progress Reports, 1936-1943; 3; 13 bound volumes
        - Markle Foundation Progress Report, January 1936-December 1938 (Box 10, Volume 1)
        - Markle Foundation Progress Report, January 1-December 31, 1939 (Box 10, Volume 2)
        - Markle Foundation Progress Report, January 1-December 31, 1940 (Box 10, Volume 3)
        - Markle Foundation Progress Report, January 1-June 30, 1941 (Box 10, Volume 4)
        - Markle Foundation Progress Report, July 1, 1941-June 30, 1942 (Box 10, Volume 5)
        - Markle Foundation Progress Report, July 1, 1942-June 30, 1943 (Box 10, Volume 6)
        - Progress Report, January 1, 1936-June 30, 1938 (Box 10, Volume 7)
        - Progress Report, July 1-December 31, 1938 (Box 10, Volume 8)
        - Progress Report, January 1-June 30, 1939 (Box 10, Volume 9)
        - Progress Report, July 1-December 31, 1939 (Box 10, Volume 10)
        - Progress Report, January 1-June 30, 1940 (Box 10, Volume 11)
        - Progress Report, July 1-December 31, 1940 (Box 10, Volume 12)
        - Progress Report, July 1, 1941-June 30, 1942 (Box 10, Volume 13)
      - Board of Directors - Collected Reprints, 1937-1941; 4; 11 bound volumes
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume I, 1937 (Box 11, Volume 1)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume II (A-M), 1938 (Box 11, Volume 2)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume III (N-Z), 1938 (Box 11, Volume 3)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume IV (A-N), 1939 (Box 11, Volume 4)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume V (O-Z), 1939 (Box 11, Volume 5)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume VI (A-I), 1940 (Box 11, Volume 6)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume VII (J-T), 1940 (Box 11, Volume 7)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume VIII (U-Z), 1940 (Box 11, Volume 8)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume IX (A-J), 1941 (Box 11, Volume 9)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume X (L-U), 1941 (Box 11, Volume 10)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Collected Reprints - Volume XI (U-Z), 1941 (Box 11, Volume 11)
    - Financial Material, 1933-1976; 2; 4 Cubic Feet 4 boxes
      This series is arranged in 3 subseries:
      Subseries 1 - Financial Reports
      Subseries 2 - Monthly Balance Sheets
      Subseries 3 - Investment Reviews
      - Financial Material - Financial Reports, 1933-1976; 1
        - 1933-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - 1940-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Financial Material - Monthly Balance Sheets, 1962-1976; 2
        - August 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - 1974-January 1976, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Financial Material - Investment Reviews, 1965-1976; 3
          - April 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
          - 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
          - 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
          - 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
          - 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
          - 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Publications, 1946-1989; 3; 0.5 Cubic Feet 2 boxes
      Materials in this series are arranged in 4 subseries according to publication type:
      Subseries 1 - Annual Reports
      Subseries 2 - President's Essays
      Subseries 3 - Markle Scholar
      Subseries 4 - Brochures
      - Publications - Annual Reports, 1946-1989 1967-1989; 1
        - 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - 1972-1973, 1973-1974, 1974-1975, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - 1976-1977, 1977-1978, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1978-1979, 1979-1980, 1980-1981, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - 1981-1982, 1982-1983, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - 1983-1984, 1984-1985, 1985-1986, 1986-1987, 1988, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous Pages from 1946-1948 and 1967-1969, 1946-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Publications - President's Essays, 1969-1989; 2
        The essays in this subseries were authored by President Lloyd Morrisett for the Markle Foundation's Annual Reports.
        - President's Essays (Box 2, Folder 11)
          "The Age of Television and the Television Age" 1969-1970
          "Cable TV: Can More be Better?" 1970-1971
          "Rx for Public Television" 1972-1973
          "Communications, Technology, and Education" 1973-1974
          "The Markle Foundation: 1975" 1974-1975
          "Radio-USA" 1975-1976
          "Sesame Street at Ten" 1977-1978
          "Getting Started in Broadcasting" 1979-1980
          "Television: America's Neglected Teacher" 1982-1983
          "The Markle Foundation: 1985" 1983/1984, 1984/1985
          "The Right to Know and the Right to Vote" 1989
      - Publications - Markle Scholar, 1976; 3
        - Markle Scholar Publications (Box 2, Folder 12)
          "Markle Scholars in Academic Medicine" 1948-1969 (2 copies)
          "The Markle Scholars - A Brief History" 1976 (2 copies)
      - Publications - Brochures, 1948-1983; 4
        - Brochures (Box 2, Folder 13)
          "Purposes and Programs" 1947
          "Charter and Constitution & By-Laws" 1960
          "Grants for Scholars in Academic Medicine" 1968
          "General Information" 1970
          "Charter and Constitution & By-Laws" 1971
          ("General Information") 1973
          "Charter and Constitution & By-Laws" (1983)
    - Presidents' Papers, 1946-1989; 4; 3 folders
      This series is arranged in 2 subseries:
      Subseries 1 - John Russell
      Subseries 2 - Lloyd Morrisett
      This series includes material documenting interests parallel to each President's work at the Foundation and non-program correspondence.
      - Presidents' Papers - John Russell, 1
        - Correspondence, 1946-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Presidents' Papers - Lloyd Morrisett, 2
        - Committee on Assessing the Progress of Education, Inc., 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Committee on Assessing the Progress of Education, Inc., 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Studies, Surveys, and Miscellaneous, 1952-1972; 5; 4 folders
      This series consists of the records of program explorations.
      - Markle Foundation Manual of Operations (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Committee on Future Plans, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Grant Photo Products, Inc., 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Summaries of Grants, 1952-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Markle Foundation Administration - Accession 2, 2; 40.8 Cubic Feet
    Series 1 - President Lloyd N. Morrisett's Papers
    Series 2 - General Office Files
    Series 3 - Board of Directors
    - President Lloyd N. Morrisett's Papers, 1927-1992 1965-1992; 1; 24 Cubic Feet 20 boxes
      This series is arranged in 5 subseries:
      Subseries 1 - Alphabetical Files
      Subseries 2 - Subject Files
      Subseries 3 - Professional Activities
      Subseries 4 - Chronological File
      Subseries 5 - Personal Files
      Lloyd N. Morrisett, who joined the Markle Foundation as president in 1969, initiated the Foundation's program in communication and information technology following the termination of the Markle Scholar Program in academic medicine. Prior to accepting his position at Markle, Morrisett was vice president of the Carnegie Corporation of New York and of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching. During his tenure with the Carnegie Corporation, he had been involved with public television projects and brought this interest and expertise to his new position. These papers document Morrisett's continuing interest, as president of the Markle Foundation, in public television and in the use of mass communication technology in education, science, and the political process.
      Except where noted, Markle Foundation folder titles and system of arrangement within folders have been maintained.
      - Alphabetical Files, 1927-1987 1965-1987; 1
        Original order has been preserved, and most of the material is filed in reverse chronological order.
        Together with Subseries 2, this subseries reflect Morrisett's service as an advisor or trustee on boards of corporations, foundations, and institutions of higher learning. Among the most notable are Children's Television Workshop, Oberlin College, RAND Corporation, Systems Development Corporation, Media Commentary Council, Haskins Laboratories, and the American Association for the Advancement of Science.
        Morrisett's role in the founding of the Children's Television Workshop (CTW), which produced "Sesame Street," "Electric Company," and other educational television programs, as well as his active participation in committees such as finance, investment, and nomination are documented. Chairman of CTW's Board of Directors since 1970, Morrisett's correspondence with Joan Ganz Cooney, Gerald Lesser, and David Brit, among others, delineates his active role in the direction and growth of the Workshop.
        As an alumnus of Oberlin College, Morrisett served as a trustee for many years and was chairman of the board of trustees from 1975-1981. In 1973 and then again in 1982, he participated in presidential search committees; his papers from the 1973 presidential search reflect an active and vocal student involvement with the process. In addition to this work on nominations, his service as trustee included work in the areas of finance and investment, admissions, and long range planning.
        Mr. Morrisett joined the board of the Systems Development Corporation in 1966 and was active during the time of the corporation's change in status from non-profit to profit. He became a board member as well of the Systems Development Foundation, which was created to carry on philanthropic efforts previously undertaken by the Systems Development Corporation. He remained a member of this board until the foundation's dissolution in 1988.
        Mr. Morrisett was a member, as well, of the Media Commentary Council beginning with its incorporation, and was involved with the publication of "Channels" magazine from its inception until the magazine's sale in 1985.
        The earlier material in this subseries, dated 1927 through 1957 (folder 101), includes articles pertaining to the field of philanthropy and are of a reference nature only.
        Throughout the materials are reflections and ideas pertaining to mass communication, education, and the growth of technology.
        - Action For Children's Television, 1975, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Advocate for the Arts, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
        - James E. Allen, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1971-1972, 1974-1975, 1979, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1971-1972, 1974-1975, 1979, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1971-1972, 1974-1975, 1979, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1971-1972, 1974-1975, 1979, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)